all right so bruce lipton
is an author how do you think the name
is title this book's right now but I
should know I've read a few of them no
one's called like spontaneous evolution
with one is the biology of belief and
how much the mind-body is connected and
he has a degree in cellular biology but
he doesn't have health issues he's never
as far as I know I read the book like a
decade ago had health issues and when I
googled it didn't just show up so it's
not definitely not front and center of
his mission on the planet and it's a
concept I mean I when I was going
through all of my health struggles and
eating fighting I had brain tumors and
then you need to get surgery and then
then growing back knee and get radiation
he can get surgery on a different one
again there was a part of me that felt
like a failure because I wasn't able to
heal them on my own because I wasn't
able to think and make them go away
because I wasn't able to like tap into
that power of the mind-body connection
and I believed in the mind-body
connection I actually think I do make my
conditions worse when I focus on them in
a negative way but I don't think I can
just reverse them the other way it's the
equivalent of like asking someone not to
think about an elephant and then of
course that's all you're gonna think
about like if you haven't been through
the struggle how would you possibly know
how to think yourself out of it
it's very different like all of these
things all of the self-help community
all of the like all of these things and
then I got even healthier how the
do you know you did you're healthy you
don't know what you had more energy like
you don't think that's a freakin placebo
effect just makes me angry this is like
all of your doctors everyone I said
tweeted this and discussing with your
friends on Facebook but Gynaecologists
used to be male doctors like a hundred
percent of them are male doctors because
a hundred percent of doctors were male
and now that women can be doctors it's
pretty much flipped like nearly a
hundred percent of the gynecologists
coming out of med school are women
because women want to see women for that
particular issue and rightfully on
sadly so but as a person who suffers
with chronic illness with mental issues
with any of that I want a doctor who
understands like just a fraction just a
little bit like who isn't a Type A
personality who and just pushed through
everything who works like 16-hour days
and that's normal and like into in
through medical school it's like no I
want someone who struggles with mental
health and and is or head like God has
gotten over it if that's possible
someone who's had health issues in the
past and now understands what it's like
to be a patient in the medical community
just like the ableism that's rampant
it's like my I just I I realize
that I definitely an anchor and like
there's a learning here it'll come but
the whole thing and I felt it in my life
is like okay everything has to be
perfect like I can eat perfect organic
food and my house needs to be clean and
organized and I need to be presentable
and because he can't tell I fall short
on all of those things like my house
especially now that I have chronic
fatigue it's like oh yeah my house
disaster I'm thought at the time me
you're lucky if I don't show up my
pajamas from the night before I probably
will choke my pajamas from the night
before and eating healthy is like yeah
eating kale smoothies all day every day
didn't make me any healthier it didn't
make the pain go away in my body didn't
give me any more energy so why I'm gonna
eat what I enjoy so that my breakfast
was this morning like I don't say so
that's exactly what you should be doing
but then watching this live call like oh
if you're not like this is only four
people are ready to like go go go go and
it's like off no you can
procrastinate
you could spend time on social media you
can have addictions and you can still
change the world where are you that's
the perfect place to be what can you do
from there if you want to change if
you're really want to have a clean house
if you really want a new look and to
that yeah that's fine but like to
require that everyone does this we're
all one human being we only know the
experience of one human being so even
with statistics and science and
everything else like Bruce Lipton's like
this works this works all the time so
what about when it does
work oh well then you're just not doing
it right no it could have worked for you
it doesn't mean it works for everyone
there's nothing on this planet that
works for any everyone and there's
probably nothing on this planet who
works for no one it's an individual
thing you cannot know what it's like to
be another human so we can only act on
compassion and we can say all of this
language of like everyone's like this or
everyone is about the most ablest thing
you can say like I don't personally from
my own individual 1 in 7.5 billion
experience I don't have a problem with
the majority of the ablest language or
the kind of like we have some ones like
you just have to like walk away to
someone who will chair right like it's
like okay well you're just like that's
your world if you're like everyone has
to be able to walk like that's the
ableism that we're dealing with and just
not like I'm done with it but it's also
why I'm here on the planet so like I
very drawn to these self-help
communities and at the same time feel
alienated in my life that no we don't
need to do it that way first of all we
can make a world where everyone
regardless of ability regardless of all
the places they are and all the spectrum
we honor our true diversity and life can
be easy for people and we don't need to
have the everything for everyone all of
the time we can be where we are amazing
and also where we're not all at the same
time anyway it's a little bit of today's